



## **Career Summary**

John is a professional with almost 11 years of experience as Web UI Developer where he has been working with programming languages such as: HTML, CSS, Vanilla JS and frameworks for every one. Also, he has some certificates in UI design. Moreover, he has creativity for problem-solving and adaptation to different environments and culture, ability to face challenges, work under pressure and good communication with the project stakeholders on the client's side, which has led him to lead some Front End teams.

# **Summary of Qualifications**

#### Proficient In:

- HTML, HTML5
- Bootstrap, Material Design Frameworks
- CSS, CSS3
- Sass, Less preprocessors
- Flexbox and Grid System
- BEM & Atomic Design methodology

- Responsive Design
- JavaScript ES6
- Angular 2+
- React JS
- Vue JS
- TypeScript
- API rest
- Redux, Vuex & NGXS state management pattern

- Unit Testing (Jest, Jazmin)
- UI Design
- Wireframes
- Mockups
- Git, GitHub, GitLab
- Jenkins
- Jira, Trello
- Scrum methodology

Jun. 2023 - Apr. 2024

# Languages

Spanish (native)

• English (B1 - intermediate)

### **Career History**

#### Globant, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Web UI Developer

MARS - Federación Patronal Seguros

Industry: Insurance

Solution Type: Migration from Oracle Forms to Web Application

Responsibilities:

- Lead the migration of Oracle Forms to Web in Angular 2+, moreover the creation and integration of new modules in the Micro Front End architecture, with the support of AI tools..
- Serve as the Technical Leader in the Front End team, promoting improvement initiatives, task coordination, and good communication with stakeholders on the client's side.
- Support in the technical and organizational integration to achieve the objectives, including collaboration with the Back End team.
- Participate in the selection of new members, promote the Scrum methodology, and the development of soft skills in the team.

Tools/Technologies: Angular 16 (Micro FrontEnd), TypeScript, SCSS, Bootstrap, NgBootstrap, REDUX pattern, GitLab



Web UI Developer Jan. 2023 – May. 2023

Paven - RoundFeather Industry: Personal Finance

Solution Type: Web responsive and Mobile

Responsibilities:

- Create and maintain reusable components in Vue JS (V.3) Composition API
- Take part to develop new features or modules inside the web application like: Debt management, Retirement, Brokerage, Buying a House (Making the layout according to Figma and integrating it with Back End development).
- Maintain greater than 80% unit test coverage with Vue Jest on new and changed components.
- Work under scrum methodology

Tools/Technologies: Vue JS (V.3) - Composition API, TypeScript, Tailwind

Web UI Developer Nov. 2022 – Dec. 2022

FitMe - Globant to Disney initiative - Globanteer

Industry: Work Interview Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Update the 'Fit Interviews List' component and integrated inside routing
- Develop code using React and Redux Toolkit
- Work under scrum methodology

Tools/Technologies: React JS (V. 16), TypeScript, Material UI

Web UI Developer Aug. 2022 – Dec. 2022

UI Katas DOJO COPE - Initiatives by UI Engineering Studio - Globanteer

Industry: Job Training

Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Build the Google Site
- Collaborate with challenges creation and guizzes for Talent Pool guys
- Participated as speaker on the first UI Engineering All Hands (15/Dec/2022), to publicize the creation of the new website.
- Create the bases to integrate Web UI TP Dojo and Mobile UI TP Dojo within the website.

Tools/Technologies: Google Sites, CSS3, JavaScript

Web UI Developer Jan. 2022 – Sep. 2022

ESPN Fantasy - Disney

Industry: Sports and Entertainment

Solution Type: Web responsive and mobile

Responsibilities:

- Make reusable components in React JS and Vanilla JavaScript
- Participate developing new features or modules inside the app & web application like: IBM Trade Analyzer with Watson, League History.
- Provide support and solving issues inside the app & web application.

Tools/Technologies: JavaScript ES6, React JS, CSS3 (SASS)



Ago. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Web UI Developer & Team Lead Temporary My Foot Print - Globant Labs - Globanteer

Industry: Environmental Solutions Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Generate reusable components in React JS
- Speed up and take part in development of new features for release V2.0
- Implement Storybook framework to organize and document existing components.
- Integrate volunteer Web UI developers within the team.
- Lead and organize new members in tasks, technical doubts and development times.

Tools/Technologies: React JS (V. 16), CSS3 (SASS), Material UI

Web UI Developer Dec. 2020 – Jan. 2022

Itau Bank – Argentina Industry: Banking

Solution Type: Web responsive and mobile

Responsibilities:

- Produce reusable components in Angular 2+
- Develop new features or modules inside the web application like as: eCheq, Investor Commons Funds, Salary Payments, Payrolls.
- Event tracking implementing Google Analytics inside the web application.
- Provide support and solving incidents or errors in the production environment, hand in hand with PO's in maintenance POD.

Tools/Technologies: Angular 2+ (V. 12), TypeScript, Jasmine unit testing

### EXSIS Digital Angels, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Nov. 2020 - Dec.2020

Web UI Developer

Industry: Educational Portals Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Create reusable components in Angular 2+
- Add visual improvements and web layout required in some educational portals
- Planning and implementation of CSS methodologies.

Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Responsive Design

### BITS Americas SAS, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Sep. 2018 – Ene. 2020

Web UI Developer

Industry: Telecommunications and Services Solution Type: Web responsive and mobile

Responsibilities:

- Lead and implement Atomic Design methodology in the project.
- Layout all design delivered by the UX design team from Miami.
- Propose GUI designs when required.
- Participate in development of modules like: Prepayment, Automatic payment, Payment to third parties, and others.
- Actively solve any visual issue in all Tigo client environments (Colombia, Honduras, Salvador, Bolivia, Paraguay, and Costa Rica).
- Web usability and accessibility consultant for other company projects.

Tools/Technologies: Angular 2+, CSS3 (SASS), Responsive Design



Industry: Marketing and E-Commerce Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Design more than 30 web pages for companies in Colombia.
- Apply a new way of designing custom web pages and break the habit of using WordPress templates.
- Interact with clients directly and sell them the designs to be implemented on the web pages to be developed.
- Community manager in the different social networks.

Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

### Soluciones Web S3G, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Oct. 2017 – May.2018

Web UI Designer

Industry: Marketing and E-Commerce Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Design and layout the back-office of a web portal for cryptocurrencies.
- Design more complex user interfaces. Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

## Management And Quality, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Dec. 2017 – Mar. 2018

Web UI Developer Industry: Marketing

Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Layout the web portal based on designs received.
- Develop the Front End part of portal. Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

### **QENTEK SAS, Bogotá D.C, Colombia**

Dec. 2017 – Feb.2018

Web UI Developer Industry: Marketing

Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Design the different screens that make up the portal.Layout the web portal based on the proposed designs.
- Develop the Front End part of portal. Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

#### DIGISTART Group, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Apr. 2016 - Jul. 2018

Web UI Developer & Web Designer Industry: Marketing and E-Commerce Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Integrate small and medium-sized companies into the digital world through web pages.
- Design the brand and digital identity for small businesses.
- Custom software development, with my participation as Front End.
- Logo design, 2D animations and multimedia composition.

Tools/Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Profamilia, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

IT Adviser Industry: Health



Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2016

Ago. 2013 - Mar. 2015

Solution Type: Trainings Responsibilities:

- Train more than 80 people in the use of the software to be implemented.
- Attention and advice to end users, regarding the software to be implemented.
- Understand the end-user when he uses software with a complex graphical interface.

Tools/Technologies: Windows 10

## Helio 4 SAS, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Web Developer Industry: Banking

Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Design some mockups for the project.Strengthen the Front End part of project
- Implement the Primefaces framework for java web applications.
- Develop Back End modules with JEE6.
- Perform CRUD transactions in databases.

Tools/Technologies: HTML, CSS, Java JSF

# Solredes Ltda, Bogotá D.C, Colombia

Web Developer

Industry: Insurances and Banking Solution Type: Web responsive

Responsibilities:

- Layout of the web app
- Develop Back End modules with JEE6 and JSE.
- Perform CRUD transactions in databases.
- Motivate the use and application of Graphic User Interface in existing projects and, thanks to this, the first graphic designer was hired.

Tools/Technologies: HTML, CSS, Java JSF

### **Education**

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá D.C, Colombia Telematics Engineer	Oct. 2021 – Dec. 2023
<b>Platzi</b> , Online Platform, Bogotá D.C, Colombia Front End Architect	Feb. 2020 – Nov.2020
<b>Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas</b> , Bogotá D.C, Colombia Diploma in Innovation, Formulation, and Project Management	Ago. 2019 – Oct. 2019
<b>Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas</b> , Bogotá D.C, Colombia Data Systematization Technologist (Software design and development)	Jul. 2009 – Oct. 2019